https://www.yacht-charter.co.uk/privacy/

About Us About UsLocationThe TeamTestimonialsYacht Charter Yacht CharterCharter FleetUK Bareboat CharterSkippered CharterCorporate Charter Corporate Chartersailing dayEventsRates RatesDiscountsSeasonal OffersLate AvailabilityStandard EquipmentProvisioning Cooking Christmas Lunch AboardRecipies for yachting Jo’s Halloumi and butter bean dishBaked Spiced Salmon with Green BeansMoroccan LambFamily CharteringAccommodationOptional ExtrasPetsCharter MembershipYacht Charter in the SunshineYacht owner services Yacht Care Services for OwnersYacht Service for OwnersManaged Yacht CharterBuyer Support ProgrammeWinter Yacht MaintenanceRYA Sailing SchoolUseful Information HPYC Policy Regarding Coronavirus (COVID-19)Booking InfoGift CertificatesPlanning your first cross-channel tripSecondary ports made easyUseful AppsBoat Maintenance- How to care for your boatWhere to SailPlaces to day sailHamble Point Marina and AreaWeather and TidesFAQLatest NewsEnvironmental overview Environmental PolicyCoastal Pump Out facilitiesEco ProductsWhat changes have we made?Contact Us
Privacy Policy
Key detailsHamble Point Yacht Charters is one of the longest established, privately owned, yacht charter companies in the UK’s premier sailing area, The Solent. We put the customer at the heart of our operations, and we take protecting your data as seriously as we take providing high-quality yachts for charter.Hamble Point Yacht Charters also owns and runs Hamble Point Sailing School and Seafin.In BriefWhen you provide us with your data, we will use it to provide you with the service(s) about which you have enquired or booked. We will use your data in a responsible and legitimate way and in a manner which you would reasonably expect.We will take reasonable steps to secure your data and will not provide your details to other organisations unless we are compelled by law to do so.  You can ask us for details of the information we hold, and you may request we make changes to incorrect or out-of-date information. You can also unsubscribe to any of our marketing emails at any time. Hamble Point Yacht Charters Privacy PolicyHow we collect, store and use your dataVisitors to our WebsiteWhen someone visits www.yacht-charter.co.uk, www.yacht-school.co.uk or www.seafin.co.uk a third party service, Google Analytics, uses a cookie to collect information about visitor behaviour. This helps us to understand how our website is being used and can help us identify which parts may need improving. We do not make, nor allow Google Analytics to make, any attempt to identify individuals from this information.Email Or Website EnquiriesIf you send us an email or submit an enquiry form through our website, you will be providing your personal contact details. We will store these details on our secure server and use them to keep you updated about the service you requested, contact you to obtain additional information ahead of a charter and to identify previous purchases in order to determine eligibility for any customer discount.We cannot guarantee the security of data transmitted over the internet and you accept this when you submit your enquiry.Booking Form Before your charter can be confirmed we will need to verify you have suitable sailing experience for a bareboat charter. We will ask you to complete a booking form which includes details of your sailing experience, qualifications, your passport and driving license numbers and we also require copies of these for our insurance.Before your charter commences we will ask you to provide additional details for you and your guests which includes an Emergency Contact name and contact details. How We Use Your Personal DataFor InsuranceWe are required, by the terms of our marine insurance, to obtain details of the nominated skipper for each charter to A Plan Insurance. We may be required to provide them with copies of your identification documents, sailing CV and certificates and contact details. You can view their Privacy Policy here.Hamble Point Yacht Charters will hold details of your sailing qualifications and experience on file to enable you to charter again in future without needing to resubmit information. You may ask us to remove this information, but should you wish to charter from us again, you would need to resupply it.For Your Wellbeing and SafetyIf you book a skippered charter or a book-a-berth cruise, you will be asked to provide details of relevant health or medical issues and, if the event is catered, any dietary requirements. This information is used to prepare appropriate catering, where relevant, and to ensure the skipper is aware of any issues which may arise during an incident whilst at sea, when medical assistance may be further awayFor Our MarketingWe will also ask you if you would like to receive our monthly email newsletter. If you agree, you will be added to our mailing list. We use a 3rd party data processor, MailChimp, to send our newsletter.You have the right to change your mind and can withdraw consent at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link within each newsletter, or by contacting us on 02380 457110 or info@yacht-charter.co.uk to request removal.  Customers who unsubscribe will still receive emails regarding their charter(s) and account.We also send a postal mailing once a year to the address you provided, which includes the latest fleet and price list. We may provide your name and address to a 3rd party mailing house to fulfil this mailing for us. If you would prefer not to receive this postal mailing, please let us know by contacting us on 02380 457110 or info@yacht-charter.co.uk to request removal.  If you opt out of postal marketing, you may still receive letters regarding your charter(s) and account.We will not pass or sell your data to anyone else for their marketing, market research or commercial purposes.Your Rights You may instruct us to provide you with any personal information we hold about you by emailing your request to info@yacht-charter.co.uk or by writing to us at: Hamble Point Yacht Charters, Hamble Point Marina, School Lane, Hamble, SO31 4JDIf you believe any of the information we hold to be incorrect or out of date, you may request us to amend or remove it.You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing emails and can unsubscribe at any time.Business TransfersIn the event of a sale, merger, consolidation, liquidation, reorganisation, or acquisition, any acquirer will be subject to our obligations under this Privacy Policy, including your rights to access and choice. We will notify you of the change either by sending you an email or posting a notice on our Website.Links to Other WebsitesOur websites contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of third party websites.ContactIf you have any questions about this privacy policy or our treatment of your personal information, please contact info@yacht-charter.co.uk or by writing to us at: Hamble Point Yacht Charters, Hamble Point Marina, School Lane, Hamble, SO31 4JDChanges to this Privacy NoticeThis privacy notice was last updated on 24th May 2018.
LATE AVAILABILITYCHARTER FLEETRYA SAILING SCHOOLGIFT CERTIFICATESPRICING & OFFERSSEAFINWHAT CLIENTS SAY
Watching the sun go down with a glass of bubbly on the deck of a sparkling yacht was unbelievable. What a treat, and a much needed change of scenery in these troubled times. We will be back for sure
What a treat (RSS)
Fab service, nothing too much trouble, including my daft questions. I'll be a repeat customer for sure!
Fab service, nothing too much trouble (ColinM)
We had a great time sailing with Lee for a few days at the beginning of September. Hamble Point Yacht Charters supplied us an impeccable 45 ft Hanse yacht, which was handled with complete mastery by Captain Lee.It was a privilege to sail with Lee, who is clearly a highly skilled professional taking great pride in his work ... but who is also a fantastic character with a great sense of humour and plenty of fun stories to keep the whole family entertained. He balances the serious side of safety and learning about sailing with a whopping dose of amusement and good cheer. We sailed the Solent in some decent seas, visited Bucklers Hard on the banks of the Beaulieu River and learned lots about British nautical history. Our boys started somewhat of a fishing trend catching bass off the back of the boat in Portsmouth and we would love to sail with Lee again in the future.The man truly knows his stuff, maintained the boat impeccably and went to every effort to ensure that we had a great time. Many thanks to “Shippers” and Hamble Point Charters. We’ll be back.
Best time sailing w/e with Lee ... many thanks to Hamble Point Yacht Charters ()
Chartered bareboats with HPYC on numerous occasions most recently in Sept 2020. Always helpful and accommodating. Highly recommend.
Always helpful and accommodating (SP)
We had a fantastic weekend sailing on Loxley B. Boat in super condition and spotlessly clean, Alex. and the team very thorough and always on hand to answer any questions. A great experience. We will be back. Thank you!
Our first but not last charter!! (CT)
Lots of information from office with a friendly service. We selected a one of the cheaper yachts and was please with find everything work and was cleaned and tidy. We will definitely be back
Very organised and friendly service (AP)
This was the first time we had tried chartering and as experienced racing sailors we didn't know what to expect. Covid has closed down all our events this year so this was a chance to get afloat at least once in 2020. What a great experience and Alex and all the Hamble staff could not have been more friendly or helpful. We had a great three days and we will be back !! We would have no hesitation is recommending Hamble Point Yacht Charters.
First ever charter - we will be back !! (LB)
From initial enquiry to handing the boat back, the service and attention to detail was fantastic. Very prompt service for the minor niggle we did have and with a wide selection of boats to charter, I'll certainly be back. One of the USPs of this business is they are right by the entrance to the Hamble so it's very quick to get out into the Solent compared to other marinas further up where it can take 30-40 mins or more just to reach Southampton water. Big thanks to Alex and the team, we had a great week on a very well kept boat
Excellent, professional outfit. Personal attention from start to finish (SP)
Professional, efficient and friendly. The booking and admin process was straightforward, the handover was well organised and Covid compliant. Most importantly the boat, a Sun Odyssey 37 was in great condition and very well equipped. We will definitely use this company again.
Great Yacht and Professional Service (AE) A short email to say thank you to you and all your team for a fantastic yacht charter and for all your help with our booking at such short notice.     Apaloosa is a lovely yacht and very well equipped.   Hamble Point Marina is a great base to explore from – and my first time sailing from there, although my husband has been a few times.I would also like to praise our skipper, Dave.    He was excellent company, very patient, great at explaining manoeuvres and very happy to involve the children so that they could learn too.    Given the weather conditions and our rusty knowledge, it was very reassuring to have him with us.   Dave was very happy to impart his knowledge and he ensured we made the most of our short charter.     We would definitely request him again!So, thank you once again, it was great fun, and have a good weekend.
Fantastic yacht charter (RP)
One of the larger charter companies which means they have a large fleet and permanent office staff, a big plus. I chartered Loxley B (37ft Sun Odyssey). Boat was clean, well equipped, well maintained. Office staff was really friendly and efficient in answering questions quickly. Will use this company again.
Friendly and professional (GV)
Thanks to all again for a great charter and the effort taken to make the handover so efficient. Especially with the videos
Great charter ()
First time using Hamble Point Yacht Charter and will definitely be back. Location, range of boats and value for money all excellent. The team was very friendly and efficient, and the boat we chartered (Blue) was in good condition and well equipped.
A weekend on Blue (JY)
Chartered 37 Hallberg Rassy for a weekend mid Jan. Booking process and communication prior to booking was friendly and informative. The yacht was immaculate and had everything we needed for the weekend. Simple check out process, lots of information provided in the personal review of the yacht. Returning the yacht was just as simple and the security deposit was refunded within 3 days. Highly recommended, we will be returning customers.
Winter weekend bareboat charter (RH)
We comprised a group of 5 friends; Chartering Kasara, a well appointed Halberg Rassy 36, for a long weekend, taking part in the Round Table Area 45 Presidents Rally.The boat was clean and ready for our arrival, and we were away in good time, she sailed well and when we returned on the Sunday evening the hand back was quick and easy.We all agreed we had had a great time, and would charter again in the future
Weekend Sailing Rally (AV)
https://www.yacht-charter.co.uk/wp-content/themes/yachtsailing
×
Contact Us
Please note: when you submit your enquiry, all details which you provide will be treated in accordance with our privacy policy.
×
Add Your Boat
Your Name (required)
Your Email Address (required)
Subject (required)
Message (required)
×
Contact Us
Please note: when you submit your enquiry, all details which you provide will be treated in accordance with our privacy policy.
×
Add Business
[contact-form-7 404 "Not Found"]
×
